Guide to the The Federal Poets records, 1944-2012 MS2322
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
The Federal Poets records
1944-2012
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
McCombs, Judith
Carsten-Miller, Ingeborg
MS2322
0.5 Linear Feet
The Federal Poets is the oldest continuously active poetry group on the Washington Metropolitan Area. Membership is open to all. Members provide critical feedback for the poet with the objective of improving each others poems. The journal The Federal Poet is published by the organization seminanually and includes the best poems submitted by members.This collection contains meeting minutes, bylaws, historical materials, correspondence and materials related to events hosted by the Federal Poets. These materials cover the very early years of the organization the early 1940s to the late 2010s. These records are not representative of the work of the organization and only document a small number of years, but do have some of the earliest materials including some written memories of the organization by members. The records cover the years 1944 through 2012.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Related Materials
The journal The Federal Poet is part of the Special Collections book and serials collection. The call no. is PS595 .W37 F43. It is housed off-site. If you have borrowing privileges you are welcome to go into the online catalog and request the box with the issues you wish to use. The Federal Poet If you do not have borrow privileges for library materials please contact Special Collections to request.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains meeting minutes, bylaws, historical materials, correspondence and materials related to events hosted by the Federal Poets. These materials cover the very early years of the organization the early 1940s to the late 2010s. These records are not representative of the work of the organization and only document a small number of years, but do have some of the earliest materials including some written memories of the organization by members. The records cover the years 1944 through 2012.
Biographical / Historical
The Federal Poets is the oldest continuously active poetry group on the Washington Metropolitan Area. Membership is open to all. The original name of the group was the Commerce Literary Society. This name was changed to the Bookfellows Club after only a few months of meetings and then in late 1946 the name again changed to The Federal Poets.
The members meet at the Tenley Public Library on the third Saturday of every month. At the meetings the group members read and discuss their poetry. Members provide critical feedback for the poet with the objective of improving each others poems. The journal The Federal Poet is published by the organization seminanually and includes the best poems submitted by members.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Judith McCombs, 2013 October 17 (2013.028). This first donation to this collection is material that originated with Ingeborg Carsten-Miller.
Future donations are expected.
Poetry; McCombs, Judith; Carsten-Miller, Ingeborg; The Federal Poets. Washington, D.C.
- Minutes of the Commerce Literary Society [1/3], 1944 August 9 - 1947 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General
  This folder contains the bylaws of the Bookfellows Club.
- Minutes of the Commerce Literary Society [2/3], 1947 May 25 - 1949 May 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes of the Commerce Literary Society [3/3], 1949 June 3 - 1957 Novemer 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- History, 1953-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  folder contains fliers, newspaper clippings, member and meeting attendance lists
- Bylaws, history and constitution, 1961-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Certificates - registration of a claim to copyright and license for non-Federal use of real property, 1965 March - 1977 August (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1975 December - 1978 January (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Strophies" National Federation of State Poetry Societies, Inc newsletters, 1975 April - 1986 January (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Meetings sign up sheets and rules for meetings, 2009 February - 2012 May (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Federal Poets Monthly, 2010 April - September (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Federal Poets reading event, 2011 April (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sign-up form and poems with notes, 2012 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 12)